foreign
triangle with sides of length a b and c
draw the inner circle of this triangle
and draw the in radii that are
perpendicular to the three sides call
the length of the in radius R the angle
bisectors meet at the in center of the
triangle and together they create these
three triangular regions which we can
unfold
each of these triangles has a height of
length R so the area of the triangle is
one half times a times R plus one half
times B times R plus one-half times c
times R factoring this out we see that
the area of the triangle is R times the
quantity a plus b plus C all divided by
two
so the area of a triangle is given by
the product of the length of the in
radius and the semi-perimeter